<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Solutions on Vidhance</title>
    <link>http://vidhance.com/solutions/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Solutions on Vidhance</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 14 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://vidhance.com/solutions/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Portable Consumer Devices</title>
      <link>http://vidhance.com/solutions/phone/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vidhance.com/solutions/phone/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;During the past few years, the smartphone market has seen a technology race in terms of camera performance, and market leading devices are now capable of near-professional still photography. Unfortunately, video performance and quality were left behind in this race.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Vidhance® software platform will enable video to make a leap in the same direction as still photography by removing unwanted movements and leaving a smooth, professional feeling in the final result.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The market for smartphones is the largest of all consumer electronics markets today, and its key role as individual expression is growing increasingly strong. Phone manufacturers, the telecom industry, and app developers all want to see progressing smartphones, where camera and video play a key role in making new models attractive to users.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Read even more about Vidhance Mobile at &lt;a href=&#34;http://vidhancemobile.com&#34;&gt;vidhancemobile.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apps and Social Media</title>
      <link>http://vidhance.com/solutions/apps/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vidhance.com/solutions/apps/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Today a huge number of apps and social media allow the user to save, process and share photos and video, but only a few can provide the user with automated suggestions on how to improve that content.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the same time, consumers wish to be able to both edit and share their experiences in the form of photos and videos with the world, and this should done as efficiently and quickly as possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Vidhance® offers stabilized video in professional quality in real time, and can also provide the user with automated suggestions on how to enhance the recorded material.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is of use not just in live streams from various events, but also for example in marketing at auction sites and e-commerce companies, or for sharing video material on social media.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Read even more about Vidhance Mobile at &lt;a href=&#34;http://vidhancemobile.com&#34;&gt;vidhancemobile.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Compression</title>
      <link>http://vidhance.com/solutions/compression/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vidhance.com/solutions/compression/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;High-quality video files still consume a relatively large amount of storage space. With stabilized and enhanced video, the small unneccessary changes from frame to frame that otherwise occur in recorded video are minimized.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This allows video compression algorithms to more easily minimize the file size and bandwidth required to store or transfer video files.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In turn this improves communication with, and storage of, video in small devices with limited storage space - such as smartphones. At the same time, video quality is dramatically improved in live scenarios such as video conferencing tools, and all private video recordings.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Air Traffic Management</title>
      <link>http://vidhance.com/solutions/airtrafficcontrol/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vidhance.com/solutions/airtrafficcontrol/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Today, civilian air traffic is monitored by air traffic controllers performing visual observations from towers. However, air traffic control is becoming more and more reliant on video feeds. Airports see more and more cameras being installed not only for traffic control, but also for security and perimeter protection purposes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;New technology and applications thereof are making it possible to concentrate ATC to a centralized and possibly remote location. Airplanes are then monitored via computer screens. Unfortunately, weather and video visibility are not always favorable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Vidhance® improves the video feed received at the remote traffic control by addressing weather effects such as fog, mist, uneven illumination etc. It also provides other video analytic functions, such as object tracking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All of this gives flight directors full access to sensors, illumination, aerial data and other flight direction tools just as if they were on location in the local flight tower.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aerial Surveillance and UAS</title>
      <link>http://vidhance.com/solutions/aerialsurveillance/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vidhance.com/solutions/aerialsurveillance/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Video from unmanned aerial systems can often be affected by disturbances such as uncontrollable movements, vibration, weather conditions, and more. Despite this, video streams of high quality are needed, where stabilization can be play a major part.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Vidhance® technology addresses these kinds of issues and provides an improved, real-time video stream to the viewer inside a ground control station or at a remote video terminal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is something we have had experience with ever since 2009. Our products have since the beginning been developed in connection with customers in several different demanding industries.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Underwater and Sub-Surface Video</title>
      <link>http://vidhance.com/solutions/underwater/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vidhance.com/solutions/underwater/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Remote-controlled underwater robots have become an essential tool in various deep sea operations. Safe control of these types of systems with high accuracy requires stabilized video streams of good quality.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Vidhance® can in real time reduce the effects of uneven illumination and improve visibility in murky waters by applying a combination of both regional and global contrast optimization.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since all video processing take place in software, there is no need for increased complexity in the deployed hardware. It can instead focus on just delivering video - Vidhance® takes care of the rest.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ground Vehicles, UGVs, and Robots</title>
      <link>http://vidhance.com/solutions/robots/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vidhance.com/solutions/robots/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Remote controlled robots, or unmanned ground vehicles, used on missions such as bomb defusal or search and rescue can suffer problems with visual disturbances affecting the video feed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Vidhance® improves the video where weather conditions, smoke, vibrations, and artificial illumination etc. impair visibility, and makes it easier for the operator to reduce the risk of missing crucial details.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>